Guide to the Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XVI: Printed Material
  - Subseries XVI.7: Books for research for plays and articles
    - For An Act of Virtue "Catholic Digest" July 1969; "Guide to the Catholic Sisterhoods" -- For Under the Sycamore Tree: Ants, Bees, and Wasps -- For The Best Butter: The Best Butter by Jean Dutourd (Box 134)
  - Subseries XVI.8: Signed and inscribed books
    - Samuel Beckett Three Plays -- E.F. Benson Peter -- Willa Cather Youth and the Bright Medusa -- Eugene O'Neill "The Emperor Jones" and "A Moon for the Misbegotten" -- Harold Pinter "The Caretaker" and "A Slight Ache and Other Plays" (Box 134:)
    - Maria (poetry by Maria Ingram) -- Offenbach "The Grand Duchess of Gerolstein" -- Archibald Henderson Mark Twain -- Byron poems -- Walter Spearman The Carolina Playmakers -- Lord Dunsany Five Plays -- John Galsworthy Plays -- Henrik Ibsen "Hedda Gabler" and other plays -- Chekhov "Rothschild's Fiddle" and other stories -- Oevres Completes de Voltaire -- Genova--Storia--Arte -- Margaret Morris Movement Magazine (Box 135:)
- Series XVII: Audio-Visual Material
  - Subseries XVII.1: Productions
    - The Enchanted Nutcracker--3 audiotapes -- Kiss Me Kate: The Making of Kiss Me Kate BBC telecast--audiotape; Symphonic Suite--2 audiotapes; Songs sung by Bob Wright--2 audiotapes; Tokyo--audiotape; Trieste, Italy--audiotape; ABC TV--2 audiotapes; Hallmark TV--3 audiotapes; Germany--2 audiotapes (Box 136:)
    - My Three Angels--2 audiotapes -- The Prince and Mr. Jones (musical version of Once There Was a Russian)--2 cassette tapes -- Under the Sycamore Tree, London production--2 audiotapes -- Stories and Articles--Bella: UNRRA Material--3 audiotapes -- Stories and Articles--Sam: The World at War--9 cassette tapes (Box 137:)
  - Subseries XVII.2: Events
    - PEF Sports Club opening and "Israel"--3 audiotapes, 2 film reels -- Sam's memorial service--"old" and "new" audiotapes -- Other: Welcome to Britain--film edited by Sam (Box 138:)
- Series XVIII: Oversize Material
  - Subseries XVIII.1: Sheet Music for Productions
    - Kiss Me Kate--printed sheet music, 4 folders -- Leave it to Me--conductor's score; printed sheet music -- Mrs. A--conductor's score -- Pleasures and Palaces (musical version of Once There Was a Russian)--printed sheet music (Box 139)
  - Subseries XVIII.2: Oversize Items from the Collection
    - Spring Song--photographs; Woman Bites Dog--photographs -- Short Stories and Articles--Bella: UNRRA--photographs -- Short Stories and Articles--Sam: "Four Years in Europe Made Me and American" printed, 2 copies; "How Johnny Gets His Gun"--printed; "Madame Luck"--printed -- Photographs--Sam and Bella, alone and with others (Box 139:)
- Series XIX: Scrapbooks
  - Boy Meets Girl -- Festival -- The Golden State -- Kiss Me Kate: American clippings #1; Brussels/Zagreb/Holland (Box 140)
  - Kiss Me Kate: American clippings #2; BBC TV production; Trieste, Italy; Film reviews (Box 141)
  - Kiss Me Kate, Sweden/Australia/Denmark/Spain/Turkey/ -- Ceylon/Japan -- Poland/Prague/Hungary -- Germany/Austria /Buenos Aires -- Britain--Sadler Wells Opera (Box 142)
  - Leave it to Me -- Clear All Wires -- Leave it to Me -- My Three Angels, 1954 (Box 143)
  - My Three Angels: 1955--U.S.A./Scotland/Great Britain/South Africa; 1952-1953; Film (Box 144)
  - Spring Song -- Under the Sycamore Tree--2 scrapbooks -- Woman Bites Dog -- Misc. (Box 145)
  - Short Stories and Articles--Bella: Articles about Bella -- Short Stories and Articles--Sam: Reviews of The Busy Busy People; 1920's news articles by Sam (Box 146)
- Series XX: Record Albums
  - The Enchanted Nutcracker--7 albums -- Festival: Opening night interview of Sam and Bella--4 albums -- Kiss Me Kate--27 albums (Box 147)
  - Kiss Me Kate--30 albums -- Leave it to Me: Collections including some songs--5 albums -- My Three Angels--2 albums (Box 148)
  - My Three Angels--5 albums -- Pleasures and Palaces (musical version of Once There Was a Russian)--2 albums -- Miscellaneous: Cat and the Fiddle--2 albums; Vogues--2 albums -- Short Stories and Articles--Bella: UNRRA reports--13 albums -- Events: PEF Sports Center opening--2 albums; Bella and Sam interview on New York Close Up--2 albums; Sam's memorial service--4 albums (Box 149)
- Series XXI: Films
  - Sam's The World at War (Box 150)
- Series XXII: Flat Boxes
  - Kiss Me Kate: Hirschfeld plate (Box 1)
- Series XXIII: Posters
  All of the posters have been reproduced in microfiche form. The fiche must be used before the original material is called for. Many of the posters are quite large.
  - Subseries XXIII.1: Boy Meets Girl
    - Photographic reproduction not on film, Court Theatre, (15 x 11 ) (Folder ID: SP1)
      [Not on fiche]
    - Master Negative Number 95-32001, Teatro Americano, (31 x 23 ) (Folder ID: SP2)
    - Master Negative Number 95-32001, Teatro Americano (2), (31 x 23 ) (Folder ID: SP3)
    - Master Negative Number 95-32001, Teatro Americano (3), (31 x 23 ) (Folder ID: SP4)
    - Master Negative Number 95-32002, Teatro Americano (4), (31 x 23 ) (Folder ID: SP5)
    - Master Negative Number 95-32003, Theater Im Zimmer: Hamburg, 1956, (16 x 12 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP6)
  - Subseries XXIII.2: Clear All Wires (Film)
    - Master Negative Number 95-32003, MGM, (41 x 27 ) (Folder ID: SP7)
  - Subseries XXIII.3: Festival
    - Master Negative Number 95-32004, Longacre Theatre: New York, (14 x 22 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP8)
  - Subseries XXIII.4: Kiss Me Kate
    - Master Negative Number 95-32004, Castellio Di San Giusto: Trieste (1), (13 x 28 ) (Folder ID: SP9)
    - Master Negative Number 95-32005, Castellio Di San Giusto: Trieste (2), (13 x 28 ) (Folder ID: SP10)
    - Master Negative Number 95-32005, Frasier Theatre: University of North Colorado, (14 x 22 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP11)
    - Not on Fiche, Frasier Theatre: University of North Colorado, (5 x 14 handbill, ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP11b)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32006, Loeb Drama Center: Cambridge, Mass., (18 x 23 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP12)
    - Not on Fiche, Loeb Drama Center: Cambridge, Mass., (18 x 23 ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP12a)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32006, Nieuw Rotterdam Toneel: Rotterdam, (18 x 26 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP13)
    - Not on Fiche, Nieuw Rotterdam Toneel: Rotterdam, (26.5 x 35.5 ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP13a)
      [Copy a and Copy b. Observable differences in poster]
    - Not Located, London: Lisceum, (26.5 x 35.5 ) (Box ?, Folder ID: SP14)
    - Not on Fiche, O'Keefe Centre, (22.5 x 14 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP15)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32008, Operettszinhaz, (19 x 27 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP16)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32008, Panstwowy Teatr, (19 x 28 ) (Folder ID: SP17)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32009, Sadler's Opera: London, (13 x 20 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP18)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32009, Shubert Theatre: New York, (14 x 23 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP19)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32010, Theatre de la Monnai: Belgium (1), (16 x 12 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP20)
      [Copy 1]
    - Not on Fiche, Theatre de la Monnai: Belgium (1), (16 x 12 ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP20a)
      [Copy 2]
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32010, Theatre de la Monnai: Belgium (2), (23 x 18 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP21)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32011, Volksoper: Vienna, (16 x 24 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP22)
    - Not on Fiche, Volksoper: Vienna, (16 x 24 ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP22a)
      [Two copies]
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32011, Castello de San Guisto: Trieste, (25 x 38 ) (Folder ID: SP23)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32012, Connaught Theatre: [Brighton?], (20 x 30 ) (Folder ID: SP24)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32012, Devlet Tiyatrosu: Turkey, (40 x 28 ) (Folder ID: SP25)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32013, Dusseldorfer Schausnielhaus: Dusseldorf, (23 x 33 ) (Folder ID: SP26)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32013, Estate Teatrale Veronese: Verona, (27 x 39 ) (Folder ID: SP27)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32014, Israel National, (26 x 42 ) (Folder ID: SP28)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32014, Kansanyeatteri: Tyovaenteatterin, (27 x 37 ) (Folder ID: SP29)
    - Not on Fiche, Kansanyeatteri: Tyovaenteatterin, (27 x 40 ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP29a)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32015, Nieuw Rotterdams Toneel: Rotterdam (1), (35 x 26 ) (Folder ID: SP30)
    - Not on Fiche, Nieuw Rotterdams Toneel: Rotterdam, (35 x 26 ) (Folder ID: SP31)
    - Naster Negative Number: 95-32016, Operett Szinhaaz, (22 x 32 ) (Folder ID: SP32)
    - Naster Negative Number: 95-32016, Panstwowy Teatr, (20 x 29 ) (Folder ID: SP33)
    - Naster Negative Number: 95-32017, Teatr Komedi, Zoliborz: Poland, (33 x 23 ) (Folder ID: SP34)
    - Naster Negative Number: 95-32017, Teatr Muzyczyn: Poznan, (23 x 33 ) (Folder ID: SP35)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32018, Unidentified Spanish Theater, (25 x 35 ) (Folder ID: SP36)
    - Not on Fiche, Unidentified Spanish Theater, (24 x 46 (2 copies) ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP36a)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32018, Japanese Production, (20 x 29 ) (Folder ID: SP37)
    - Not on Fiche, Japanese Production, (20 x 29 ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP37a)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32019, Teatro Avenida: Argentina, (58 x 45 ) (Box Table, Folder ID: SP38)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32020, Volksoper: Vienna, 1960, (48 x 34 ) (Box Table, Folder ID: SP39)
  - Subseries XXIII.5: My Three Angels
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32021, Morosco Theatre: New York, (14 x 22 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP40)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32021, Unidentified Hebrew Production, (19 x 27 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP41)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32021, Unidentified Hebrew Production, (19 x 27 ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP41a)
  - Subseries XXIII.6: Once There Was a Russian
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32022, National Theatre: Washington, D.C., (14 x 22 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP42)
  - Subseries XXIII.7: Poppa
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32022, Teatro Nrovo: Milan (1), (14 x 39 ) (Folder ID: SP43)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32023, Teatro Nrovo: Milan (2), (28 x 39 ) (Folder ID: SP44)
  - Subseries XXIII.8: Two Blind Mice
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32023, Court Theatre: New York, (14 x 23 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP45)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32024, Court Theatre: New York, (11 x 14 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP46)
      [Unidentified sample poster]
  - Subseries XXIII.9: Under the Sycamore Tree
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32024, Aldwych Theatre: London, (13 x 20 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP47)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32025, Alleteatern: [Stockolm], (16 x 19 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP48)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32025, His Majesty's Theatre: Aberdeen, 1952, (14 x 25 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP49)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32026, Lyceum Theatre: Edinburgh, (10 x 15 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP50)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32026, Theatre Royal: Brighton, (10 x 30 ) (Folder ID: SP51)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32027, Theatre Royal: Newcastle upon Tyne, 1952, (13 x 25 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP52)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32027, Aldwych Theatre: London, (21 x 35 ) (Folder ID: SP53)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32028, Plaza Theatre: Maritius, (19 x 28 ) (Folder ID: SP54)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32028, Teatre Odeon: [Milan?], (15 x 45 ) (Folder ID: SP55)
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32029, Theatre Royan: Newcastle, 1952, (21 x 34 ) (Folder ID: SP56)
  - Subseries XXIII.10: Woman Bites Dog
    - Master Negative Number: 95-32029, Ford's Theatre, (14 x 22 ) (Box Box, Folder ID: SP57)
  - Subseries XXIII.11: The Sensational Sacco Vanzetti Case
    - Not on Fiche, (30 x 40 (approx.) ) (Box Roll, Folder ID: SP58)